昨天晚上我跟露西视频
So, anyway, last night on video chat,
我盯着她的双眸足足有二十分钟
I spent, like, 20 minutes just staring into Lucy's eyes.
听起来很浪漫啊
Oh, that sounds romantic.
后来发现是画面卡了  就毫无浪漫可言了
It was until I realized the screen had frozen.
但这还是我这辈子最棒约会的前三名
Still one of my top three dates of all time.
她什么时候会来跟大伙聚聚啊
So, are we ever gonna hang out with this girl?
我也想啊
I'd love that,
但她实在不太善于与人交流
but she's not really comfortable around people.
我以前也跟她一样不善与人交流
Yeah, I used to be uncomfortable around people,
后来学到一个小诀窍
but then I learned a trick.
我把认识的每个人
I pretend everyone I meet
都看作是《星际迷航》里受欢迎的角色
is a beloved character from Star Trek.
那这招管用吗
How's that been working for you?
当然好用啊  你个无名红衣机组人员
Oh, like a charm, unnamed crewman in a red shirt.
莱纳德  我可能帮你弄到了份工作
Leonard, I may have gotten you a job.
-我有工作了  -他真的有哦
- I have a job. - Yes, he does.
工作就是服务我的一切要求
He caters to my every whim.
不  再过几周  史蒂芬·霍金要
No, in a couple of weeks, Stephen Hawking's team
送一对远征实验队伍去北海
is sending an expedition to the North Sea
做黑洞的流体动力学模拟
to test hydrodynamic simulations of black holes.
队伍中有一名实验物理学家退出了
One of their experimental physicists dropped out,
所以我就推荐了你
and I recommended you.
你觉得我真有机会雀屏中选吗
Well, do you really think I have a shot?
我跟霍金共事过  说了你不少好话呢
Yeah, I've worked with Hawking. I talked you up.
他知道你的研究
He knows your research.
我觉得希望非常大
I think this could happen.
他居然知道...  哇
He knows-- Wow!
你觉得这真是个好主意吗
Well, now, but do you think that's a good idea?
我觉得行  你也知道《星际迷航》
I do. Uh, you know Star Trek.
一个没有角色名字
Should a guy with no name
穿着普通制服的人适合去参加实验吗
and a red shirt really go on an expedition?
别这样打击他
Hey, don't discourage him.
这是他千载难逢的好机会呢
This is a fantastic opportunity.
没人问你  女通讯官乌乎拉
No one asked you, Uhura.
想听听谢尔顿招牌亦假亦真小讲堂吗
Would you like to hear a classic Sheldon Cooper factoid?
-你说呢  -很好
- What do you think? - Great.
我最近读了不少交通工具安全
I've been doing some reading about vehicular safety.
你知道溺水的最高几率的
Did you know that the highest number
发生地点是在船上或是船附近吗
of drowning accidents happen on or around boats?
在我很有可能去船上工作前
Interesting that you would bring that up
你提起这事  时机很巧妙啊
when I might go work on a boat.
亦假亦真就是这样的
Well, that's the thing about factoids--
听起来就很巧妙
they're interesting.
我知道你的小算盘
I know what you're doing.
你不想我去这个实验之旅
You don't want me going on this research trip
因为你害怕自己独处
because you're afraid to be alone.
我才不害怕自己独处
I'm not afraid to be alone.
在陆地就不怕
On land.
在海上呢  这就可怕了
On the sea, it would be terrifying.
太容易溺死了
Because of all the drowning.
谢尔顿
Sheldon.
行  我不提溺水了
Fine, no more drowning talk.
我换个话题
I'll change the subject.
你觉得这两者打架  谁能赢呢
Who do you think would win in a fight--
你或鲨鱼
you or a shark?
我感谢你这招牌的
Look, I appreciate your signature blend
"为我着想"与"超级自私"
of concern for me and incredible selfishness.
如果我能有机会入选
If I get the chance to do this,
你说什么都没办法阻止我去的
there is nothing you can say that's going to stop me.
非常好
Very well.
你与佩妮的感情现在好到不行
Things between you and Penny have never been better.
我只希望四个月的分离不会改变这一切
I hope four months apart doesn't change anything.
我应该先提这件事的对吧
I should have opened with that, huh?
生活大爆炸
第六季  第二十四集[本季终]
如果你仔细看向金星
If you look carefully at Venus,
你应该能看见
you should be able to see
国际太空站从它面前经过
the International Space Station pass by.
你朋友真去过那上面吗
Your friend was actually up there?
他还带了一件T恤给我  上面写着
Yeah. He brought me back a T-shirt that said,
"我朋友上了国际太空站
"My Friend Went to the Space Station
而我只有拿到这件傻逼T恤"
and All I Got Was This Lousy T-Shirt""
-他有带那件T恤上太空吗  -没有
- Did he take the T-shirt to space? - Nope.
但那衣服绝对够傻逼
It's exactly as lousy as advertised.
说到朋友
Speaking of friends,
我的朋友们想见见你呢
they have been asking to meet you.
我想着或许
I was thinking
有机会我们大家一起聚一聚吧
maybe we could all hang out sometime?
我不知道
I don't know.
你有多少朋友啊
How many are there?
我算算  六个
Let's see. Six.
哇  好酷  我有六个朋友呢
That's pretty cool; I have six friends!
有点像西纳特拉
Kind of like Sinatra.
西纳特拉  美国上世纪杰出男歌手
有过一档与7名好友歌唱的节目  名为"西纳特拉与好友们'
六个陌生人
Six strangers?
这压力好大啊
That's a lot of pressure.
盯着我看  问我一堆私人问题
Staring at me, asking me personal questions.
比如"你做什么工作的"
Like, "What do you do?"
"你从哪里来的"
"Where are you from?"
"你为什么要把自己锁在厕所里呢"
"Why did you lock yourself in the bathroom?"
要不你就先见其中一个
Okay, how about you just dip your toe in
看看情况如何
and meet one of them?
你会来吗
Will you be there?
当然啊
Of course.
那就是两个陌生人  算我自己就三个
Well, that's two. Three if you count me.
这事情越来越失控了
Oh, this is getting out of hand.
在我下午上班的时候
So, then, during my afternoon shift,
我不小心把整托盘的饮料全撒身上了
I spilled an entire tray of drinks on myself.
好惨啊
Oh, that's awful.
也没有啦  靠着湿透的衣服
Not really. My shirt was soaking wet.
我拿到了我这辈子最多的小费呢
I got, like, the biggest tip of my life. Oh.
你还记得我跟你说过有关
So, listen, do you remember when I said
广义相对论与流体力学
the similarities of the equations
方程中的相似处表示了
of general relativity and hydrodynamics suggest
在有巨量水源的地方很可能能找到
you could find the equivalent of Unruh radiation
盎鲁射线的相似物
in a large body of water?
这不是我跟你说的吗
I thought I said that to you.
总而言之
Anyway,
史提芬·霍金的队伍在研究这个
Stephen Hawking's team is looking into that,
而他们要请我加入
and I've been invited to join them.
霍金呢  恭喜你
Wow, Hawking! Good for you!
是很好
Well, it is.
但是  这样我就得离开一阵子
Just-- you know, I'd be gone for a while.
多久呢
Well, how long?
三四个月吧
Three, four months.
-什么时候走  -再过几周吧
- When would you leave? - Couple weeks.
没事  那我去看你好啦
O-Okay, well, I'll just come visit you.
这就是问题所在  你不能来
That's the thing-- you can't.
因为我会在北海的一艘船上
I'll be on a ship in the North Sea.
在船上
On a ship?
不怕坐在轮椅上的霍金  会从甲板上滚下去吗
Aren't they afraid Hawking will just roll overboard?
他不会去
Uh, he's not gonna be there.
他只是派人去研究他的理论
He's just sending a team to research his theory.
当然
Oh, sure.
就像你派我去打死你浴缸的蜘蛛一样
Like when you send me to kill spiders in your bathtub.
好吧  整整四个月
Okay. Four months.
是的
Yeah.
我有点担心
And I'm a little worried
因为咱们俩现在感情这么好
because things between us have been so great,
我不想做任何会破坏感情的事情
and I'd hate to do anything that screws that up.
亲爱的  一般会破坏感情
Oh, sweetie, if you're gonna screw things up,
都是你在的时候  你不在时万事大吉
it's gonna be while you're here, not while you're away.
没关系  你必须得去
No. I mean, look, you have to go.
听起来这是个很棒的机会
It sounds like an amazing opportunity.
我之所以这么说  是因为
And I'm just basing that on how much
我一点也不懂你刚说的话
I didn't understand what you said about it.
好吧
Okay.
我明天早上会确认行程安排
I'll confirm the travel arrangements in the morning.
好  很好
Okay. Good.
-我需要你帮我做件事  -说吧
- I do have to ask you one favor. - Sure.
谢尔顿对我的离开很不安
Sheldon's nervous about me leaving.
我不在的时候  记得帮我照顾下他
Just keep an eye on him while I'm gone.
我不知道
Oh, I don't know.
还记得以前我是怎么照顾你的金鱼的吗
Remember what happened when I took care of your goldfish?
那就把谢尔顿冲下马桶  再给我买个新的
Well, flush Sheldon down the toilet and get me a new one.
真的  你们真没必要帮我弄个告别派对
Really, you guys do not need to throw me a going-away party.
开什么玩笑
Are you kidding me?
人生能有几次跟真正去大海航行的人
How often can you say "bon voyage" to somebody
说"一路[航行]平安"
when they're actually going on a voyage?
你好  拉杰
Hello, Rajesh.
你好  艾米  很高兴见到你
Hello, Amy. Nice to see you.
那又怎么样  带口音比较好玩嘛
What can I say? It's funnier with the accent.
冰箱里有啤酒
There's beer in the fridge.
总之你们真的不必小题大作
Anyway, you guys really don't need to make a big deal.
莱纳德  你太自私了
Leonard, you're being selfish.
我们必须得举行一个告别仪式  等你死在海里
We need to give you a proper send-off so we'll have closure
脸被螃蟹吃掉的时候  我们也有个解脱
when you die at sea and crabs eat your face.
谢尔顿  麻烦把嘴闭上
Sheldon, sweetie, shut up.
霍华德当年上太空那么久
You know, one of the things
支撑我熬过这段时间的其中一件事
that helped me get through Howard being in space
就在他走之前跟他结婚
for so long was getting married before he left.
伯纳黛特  麻烦把嘴闭上
Bernadette, sweetie, shut up.
好了
Okay.
我有一件事想麻烦大家
I have a request to make.
现在他居然可以说话了
And now he can talk.
我真想切开你的脑子
I want to cut open your brain
看看里面到底是怎么回事
and see what the heck's going on in there.
唯一能检查[进入]我脑子的人是菲尔博士
The only person allowed inside this head is Dr. Phil.
菲尔博士是有博士学位的心理医生
专门在电视上帮别人解决家庭问题
总之
Anyway, I-
我跟我的新女友说要带她来见你们
I spoke to my new lady friend about meeting you all,
她觉得先见你们其中一个
and she thought it would be easier for her
会比较不让她害怕
to start with just one.
我可不知道有没有时间
Oh, gee, I don't know.
我的日程有点满
My schedule's a little busy.
其实我是想让她先见莱纳德
Actually, I was thinking Leonard.
谢谢  拉杰  我非常荣幸
Thank you, Raj. I'd be honored.
我擦咧
What the hell?
我以为我才是你最好的朋友
I thought I was your best friend.
你是啊  但你的个人特色过于鲜明
You are, but you've got kind of a big personality,
你看你花哨的衣服和那吊儿郎当范儿
with your flashy clothes and your Woody Allen swagger.
或许先跟女生见面  她会更放松
You know, maybe she'd be more comfortable meeting a girl first.
好主意  伯纳黛特
Good idea. Bernadette?
我擦咧
What the hell?!
你长得非常漂亮
Well, you're very pretty.
这会让其他女性有威胁感
That could be intimidating to another woman.
也对
Oh, yeah.
你觉得我不够漂亮  不会吓着你的女朋友吗
Hey, you don't think I'm pretty enough to scare your girlfriend?
冷静  妮妮
Calm down, Bernie.
你非常吓人
You're very scary.
-应该让我去  -为什么
- It should be me. - Why?
好让你开把我脑子切开的玩笑吗
So you can make jokes about cutting open my brain?
首先  那可不是开玩笑
A, that was not a joke.
那是个真诚的请求
That was a sincere request.
其次  更重要的是
And B, more importantly,
我曾经是这个小团体中的局外人
I was the outsider to this group,
我知道初次见面的感觉有多可怕
and I know how frightening that can be.
但你们接纳我  让我感受到你们的爱
But you guys took me in and made me feel loved,
就像家人的爱一样
like I was family.
好啦  我去就是了
Fine, I'll do it.
在我开始跟谢尔顿约会之后
So, after I started dating Sheldon,
我认识了莱纳德  还有其他人
I met Leonard, and then everybody else,
他们都对我非常好
and they've all been so wonderful to me.
听起来真不错
That's really nice to hear.
或许下周  我们可以一起聚聚
Maybe next week, we could all get together.
露西  你可以不用回答
Oh, Lucy, you don't have to answer that.
别把她逼到这个份上  她不喜欢这样
Don't put her on the spot. She hates that.
我说得对吗
Am I right?
告诉她你有多不喜欢被人逼着去交际
Tell her how much you hate being put on the spot.
快啊  告诉她
Go ahead, tell her.
别搭理他
Ignore him.
他有点紧张  因为他觉得我不明白
He's a little nervous 'cause he doesn't think I understand
你社交焦虑症的严重程度
the severity of your social anxiety.
搞毛呀  你疯了吗
What the...? Are you crazy?
你不能跟有社交焦虑症的人
You can't talk about social anxiety
谈论社交焦虑症
to someone who has social anxiety.
这会让他们更加焦虑的
It makes them socially anxious!
不好意思  但我是个神经生物学家
Excuse me, but I'm a neurobiologist.
我觉得我比你更懂得
I think I'm a little more qualified than you
你女朋友的脑子里的毛病在哪里
to understand what's not working in your girlfriend's brain!
别说她是我的女朋友
Don't call her my girlfriend.
我们还没正式说过
We haven't discussed whether or not
我们到底是不是男女朋友呢
we're girlfriend or boyfriend yet.
既然这话题已经提出来了
Now that it's out there...
你是我的女朋友吗
...are you my girlfriend?
顺便说一下  如果你说"不是"
By the way, if you say no,
那我会伤心郁闷一辈子哦
I'll never be happy again.
我可不是逼你哦
Not to put you on the spot.
我想去个厕所
I think I have to go to the bathroom.
我们可以先开始吃了
We might as well go ahead and eat.
她短时间内不会回来了
She's not coming back anytime soon.
真是可笑
This is ridiculous.
我们为派对购物
We're shopping for a party.
可这商店都没有"派对专区"
This store doesn't even have a party section.
有的有的  就在这儿
Yeah, it does, and here we are.
佩妮  我不得不说
You know, I have to say, Penny,
我真不明白你怎么会
I don't understand why you of all people
鼓励莱纳德去那个项目
are encouraging Leonard to do this.
我是他的女朋友  当然要支持他啦
Well, I'm his girlfriend; of course I'm gonna support him.
你只是他现在的女朋友而已嘛
Yeah, well, you're his girlfriend for now.
你可能还不了解形势
You know, maybe you're not aware of this,
但根据悠久的传统
but there is a rich tradition
出海人很能在他人的双臂双腿间找寻安慰
of men at sea finding comfort in each other's arms and britches.
亲爱的  这对莱纳德很重要
Honey, this is a big deal for Leonard, okay?
他将会与史蒂芬·霍金共事
He gets to work with Stephen Hawking.
另外  霍金不会上船
Who, by the way, will not be on the boat.
我查清了
I checked it out.
这机会也不算千载难逢
It's not that big of an opportunity.
就算霍金的理论是正确的
And even if Hawking's theories are correct,
那他证明也无非是宇宙是从哪来的
all they prove is where the universe came from,
万物存在的原因及宇宙的尽头
why everything exists and what its ultimate end will be.
而我
I mean, me?
我感兴趣的是更宏观的问题
I'm interested in the big questions.
上帝啊  天才谢尔顿竟然嫉妒莱纳德
Oh, my God, Sheldon the genius is jealous of Leonard.
我才没嫉妒
I'm not jealous.
我只是不开心
I'm just very unhappy
好事情发生在他身上
that good things are happening for him
却没我的份
and not happening for me.
亲爱的  有这种感觉很正常
Look, sweetie, this is a natural thing to feel, okay?
但莱纳德身上有好事发生
But just because good things are happening to Leonard
不代表你会损失什么啊
doesn't take anything away from you.
我给你讲个故事吧
You know what? Let me tell you a little story.
从前有个在起司工厂工作的女孩
Once there was a girl who worked at the Cheesecake Factory,
她对自己的工作不怎么擅长
and she wasn't very good at her job.
-是你  -不是我
- It was you. - It wasn't me.
但她同样也是个演员
But she was also an actress,
我们都是某支牙膏广告的
and we were both up for the same part
候选人
in a toothpaste commercial.
她拿到了  我特别嫉妒
She got it. Look, I was so jealous.
但我没有扯掉她那一头假冒的金发
But instead of ripping out her fake blonde hair...
你扯掉了自己那一头假冒的金发
You ripped out your own fake blonde hair.
我
I...
看着她的眼睛
looked her in the eye,
笑着说  "我真为你高兴"
smiled and said, "I'm happy for you."
因为朋友就该这样
Because that's what friends do.
-为了不显得小气而说谎  -对
- They lie so they don't look petty. - Yeah.
-要怎么做  -像这样
- How? - Like this.
我太为你开心了
I am so happy for you.
怪不得牙膏广告没选上你
No wonder you didn't get that toothpaste commercial.
我想为艾米昨晚的表现道歉
I want to apologize for Amy last night.
她太过分了
She was completely out of line.
是你没说话
Are you... are you not speaking to me
还是画面又卡住了
or did the screen freeze again?
根本不关艾米的事
Amy wasn't the problem.
好吧  我知道
Okay. I know.
是我不好
It was me.
我把你逼得太紧了  对不起
I-I pushed too hard. I'm sorry.
谢谢理解
Thank you.
我在想
You know, I-I've been thinking that...
也许一对一地见他们太让人紧张了
maybe meeting somebody one-on-one is too intense,
所以
so...
我的朋友们周五会举办个派对
Friday night, my friends are having a party.
-派对  -小型的
- A party? - A little one!
是为了给莱纳德饯行
It's-it's a farewell for Leonard,
所以大家只会关注他
so all the attention will be on him.
如果你穿棕色的衣服  往沙发上一坐
If you wear something brown and sit on the couch,
他们压根就不会发现你的存在
they won't even know you're there.
我不确定
I'm not sure.
-拜托了  -拉杰
- Oh, please? - Raj.
拜托啦  真要让我求你啊
Come on. Don't make me beg.
我来自印度  我可懂怎么求人了
And I'm from India, so I know how to do it.
好吧
Okay.
谢谢
Y... Thank you!
这对我意义重大
Th-This means a lot to me.
我的朋友就像家人一样
My friends are like my family.
除非你不喜欢他们
Unless you don't like them;
那样的话  他们对我毫无意义
in which case, they're dead to me.
你以前在船上长时间待过吗
So, have you ever spent a long time on a boat before?
-待过  -你说的是那次
- Yeah. - Are you referring to the time
我们在迪士尼玩小小世界的时候船卡住不动吗
we got stuck on the Small World ride at Disneyland?
是的
Yeah.
你真让我自豪  莱纳德
I'm proud of you, Leonard.
在北海工作几个月
Working out on the North Sea for months--
-这可真了不起  -我知道
- that's really something. - I know.
不管科学研究得如何
As far as science goes,
这可是百年不遇的经历啊
this is the adventure of a lifetime.
对你可能是的
Maybe your lifetime.
反正我是去过太空了
I went to space.
这可没什么可比的
It's not a competition.
你说得对
You're right, you're right.
我真为你感到骄傲
I'm really proud of you, and...
你去了以后我会想你的
I'm gonna miss you when you're gone.
另外太空可比大海牛
And space beats water.
拉杰什  我以为露西会来呢
Rajesh, I thought Lucy was coming.
她要来的  只不过稍微迟到了点
She is. She's just running a little late.
你知道的  女孩子出门总要花时间
You know how it is-- girls always fussing about
弄头发啊  化妆啊啥的
their hair, their makeup.
她会来的
She'll be here.
别老问了  好吗
Just give it a rest, okay?
大家请注意
Um, can I have your attention, everyone?
给没有绝对音感的人  这是降B调
That's, uh, B-flat, for those who don't have perfect pitch.
我想给我最好的朋友
I would like to propose a toast
莱纳德·霍夫斯塔德敬一杯酒
to my best friend, Dr. Leonard Hofstadter.
他现在得到了一个弥足珍贵的机会
He has been presented with a wonderful opportunity,
我非常为他高兴
and I couldn't be happier for him.
谢谢  谢尔顿
Thank you, Sheldon.
你能说出这话真不容易
That must've been very hard for you to say.
我是真心的
Well, I mean it.
我真的很为你高兴
I'm really happy for you.
你得这样才能拿下那牙膏广告  干杯
And that's how you get a toothpaste commercial. Cheers.
干杯
Cheers.
你能为莱纳德高兴  真是不错
It was really nice of you to try to be happy for Leonard.
谢谢
Thank you.
我上太空时  你肯定是眼红到不行吧
It must've killed you when I went to space.
不好
Oh, no.
兄弟  没事吧
Buddy, you okay?
老天
Oh, man.
出什么事了
What's going on?
念出来吧
Uh, go ahead. Read it.
"拉杰  我不能来参加派对
"Raj, I can't come to the party.
这对我来说  难以承受
This is all just too much for me.
我觉得我们还是不要再见面了
I don't think we should see each other anymore.
对不起  露西"
Sorry. Lucy."
失陪下
Excuse me.
拉杰  太遗憾了
Raj, I'm so sorry.
别太难过
Me, too.
你上太空时  我才没有眼红呢
It did not kill me when you went to space.
猴子都上过太空
Monkeys went to space.
到机场了
Well, here we are.
是的
Yep.
我会非常想你的
I'm really gonna miss you.
我也会想你的
I'm gonna miss you, too.
佩妮  我们在红线区
Penny, we're in the red zone.
白线区才是上下车区
The white zone is for loading and unloading.
我们现在犯法了
We're breaking the law.
-白线区没地方了  -总之
- Okay, there's no space in the white zone, so... - Anyway,
我们可以发电邮  那里的手机信号
we can E-mail, and I-I think the phone connections
应该也不错
are pretty good.
好了  你赶紧下车吧
All right, you have to get out of the car right now.
我不会为了你去坐牢的
I'm not going to jail for you.
你放轻松行吗
Would you just relax?
白线区空出来一个位置
Oh, I see a space in the white zone.
快  绕机场一圈冲上去
Quick, circle the airport.
呼吸器带的够吗
Did you bring enough inhalers?
够
Yeah.
额外的晕船药呢
And, uh, extra Dramamine?
你还记得那次小小世界的事故吧
You remember what happened on It's a Small World.
-带了  -好的
- I'm covered. - Okay.
老天爷  一个警察冲我们
Oh, dear Lord, a police officer's
这个方向扫了一眼
glancing in our direction.
我们死定了
We've been made.
冷静下  我下车了
Calm down. I'm getting out.
我要送你件礼物
I have something I want to give you.
莱纳德
Oh, Leonard.
只是一个心形的相盒吊坠项链
It's just a heart-shaped locket with a picture of
里面有莱纳德的照片  他在商场清仓时买的
Leonard's face in it. He got it at the mall on clearance.
快下车吧
Now move, move, move!
我爱你
I love you.
我也爱你
I love you, too.
别担心  警官
Don't worry, Officer.
他们只是彼此相爱
They just love each other.
我们没有贩毒
We're not smuggling drugs.
拉杰  我是佩妮
Raj, it's Penny.
你在家吗
Are you in there?
稍等
Hang on.
我刚从机场回来
Hey. I'm just coming back from the airport.
过来看看你怎么样了
I wanted to see how you're doing.
你真好
That's-that's very nice of you.
进来吧
Uh, come, come. Come on in.
我不能待太久
Can't stay long.
我把谢尔顿留在车上了  虽然车窗有开一条缝
I left Sheldon in the car with the window cracked open.
那本儿童活动书他应该只用
He's gonna go through that activity book
30秒就能看完
in, like, 30 seconds, so...
你还好吗
Are you okay?
不好
No.
我真替你难过
I'm so sorry.
不
No.
这是我的错
It's my fault.
我终于找到了适合我的人
You know, I finally found someone who was right for me,
我却把她吓跑了
and I-I drove her away.
拉杰
Oh, Raj.
佩妮  我...
Penny, I...
我已经开始想她了
I miss her already.
我明白你的感受
I know how you feel.
我也开始想莱纳德了
I miss Leonard, too.
我到底有什么问题啊
What's... what is wrong with me?
为什么我就是不能拥有爱情呢
Why-why can't I ever have love?
你会的
You will.
不  我不会的
No, I... I won't.
没人会爱我
I'm-I'm unlovable.
你是酒喝多了才会这么说
That's just the booze talking.
不是的
No, it's not.
昨晚后我就没喝酒了
I haven't had a drink since last night.
-你在和我说话  -是的
- You're talking to me. - I am.
现在我为了完全不同的原因痛哭流涕了
And now I'm crying for a whole different reason!
我也是
Me, too!
我想我要说的就是
So I-I guess what I'm saying is.
我理解露西的出发点
I get where Lucy's coming from.
很好  要来杯红酒吗
That's great. Do you want some wine?
不用  喝水就行了
Uh, no, water's fine.
总之  我想了很多
Anyhow, I-I've been thinking about it a lot,
我完全理解露西为什么这样做
and-and I totally see why Lucy did what she did.
我给的压力太大了
I pushed too hard.
如果我稍稍放手  给她足够的空间
But you know what? If I back off and give her enough space,
也许我们之间还有未来可言
maybe there's still a future for us.
人生好笑的地方就在于
Yeah, the funny thing about life is that,
有时候...
you know, sometimes...
他还会闭嘴吗
Does he ever shut up?
然后  事情又出现转机
And then, it turns good again,
这比一帆风顺的感觉又会好些
that means it better than if never been bad for a while,
现在  情况就是
and now, things are going...
非常非常的糟糕
in fact, are very very bad.
但至少我的心开始愈合了
But at least my heart is starting to heal.
一步步地慢慢愈合
Slowly but surely.
开始我那叫哭得一个惨啊
And how I cried.
我的脸上就好像来了场暴风雨
It was like a little, uh, thunderstorm on my face.
但我好歹算个男人
But I'm a man, okay?
我需要收拾心情  拿起笔
So I need to pull myself together, pick up a pen
把一切心情都写在日记上
and get it all out in my journal.
而且并不全是坏事  对吗
I mean, it's not all bad, right?
我心碎的结果
Having my heart broken
就是令我终于能在你们面前滔滔不绝
has allowed me to finally speak in front of you...
瞧  我终于找到了乌云背后的幸福线
so, you know, it was a silver lining.